<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>


<document>
   <properties>
      <title>How To: Use MPXJ with .Net</title> 
      <author email="jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">Jon Iles</author> 
   </properties> 

   <body> 

<section name="How To: Use MPXJ with .Net">
<p>MPXJ ships with both a Java library (mpxj.jar) and also a .Net DLL (mpxj.dll), 
which can be found in the lib.net folder of the distribution. To use MPXJ
from a .Net language, simply ensure that the DLLs present in the lib.net 
folder are all added as references to your project.</p>

<p>MPXJ ships with some sample files which can be found in the src.net
folder of the distribution. These files illustrate how the MPXJ API can be 
used to manipulate project data. In particular the MpxjQuery sample files
show how various elements which make up the project data can be queried.
Two versions of this utility are present in src.net, one written in C#,
and the other written in Visual Basic (VB) to illustrate the basics of using
MPXJ in either language. Even if you are developing software in a .Net
language you may still find it useful to refer to the Java examples, and
indeed the original Java source of MPXJ to give you an insight into how the
API may be used.</p>

<p>The .Net version of MPXJ has been generated directly from the Java
version using a tool called IKVM. One of the side effects of using IKVM to
perform this conversion is that the MPXJ exposes .Net versions of the
original Java data types, so for example you will find that the API returns
a type called Date rather than a .Net DateTime, and collections which 
don't expose the familiar IEnumerable interface.</p>

<p>To try and make the use of MPXJ as natural as possible for .Net developers,
two specific areas have been addressed. The first area is the MPXJ API itself: 
in the original Java version of the code you will find that properties use 
accessor and modifier methods like those shown below:</p>
<source>
String text = task.getText();
task.setText(text);
</source>
<p>In the .Net version of the API, in most cases you will find that .Net properties
are available, so the Java style methods do not need to be used:</p>
<source>
String text = task.Text
task.Text = text;
</source>
<p>The other area of assistance provided to .Net developers is a simple 
set of extension methods. In the Visual Studio project found in the src.net
folder, a project called MpxjExtensionMethods is present. This project contains
extension methods which enhance both Java and .Net classes to make it easier to
pass data to and from the API. For example the extension method ToIEnumerable 
is added to Java collection data types which allows them to be iterated using 
the familiar foreach .Net syntax.</p>

<p>To use these extension methods, simply add a reference to the 
MpxjExtensionMethods assembly
in your own project. The methods themselves are documented in the source, and
examples of their use can be seen in the samples provided in the src.net folder.</p>
</section>
</body>
</document>




