<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>


<document>
   <properties>
      <title>Building MPXJ</title> 
      <author email="jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">Jon Iles</author> 
   </properties> 

   <body> 

<section name="Introduction">
<p>Although MPXJ can be downloaded as a complete package from SourceForge,
the development of the library continues between releases and is driven by
user requests for new functionality, and bug fixes being applied to existing
features. Many MPXJ users will work with and ship software based on 
intermediate versions of MPXJ built from the code in CVS in order to take
advantage of these enhancements before they become available in an official 
release. This approach is supported by the fact that code is only checked into 
CVS if the suite of JUnit regression tests have been completed successfuly: 
therefore the quality of the code taken from CVS at any point can be guaranteed 
to be as good as that in an official release.</p>

<p>In order to take advantage of MPXJ functionality from CVS, you will need to 
understand how to build the library, whether you are using it in the form
of a Java JAR or a .NET DLL. The following sections explain how to do this.</p>
</section>

<section name="Building the Java JAR">
<p>The MPXJ build process is based on the use of an Ant script. If you aren't 
familiar with Ant, it is script execution tool similar in concept to 
make or nmake. 
The prerequisites for building MPXJ are:
<ul>
	<li>A Java Development Kit (JDK) - at the minimum Java 1.6 is required.  
	A suitable JDK can be downloaded from <a href="http://java.sun.com/" target="_blank">http://java.sun.com</a></li>
	<li>Apache Ant. I use version 1.7.1, but the ant build script will probably 
	work happily with older versions. Ant can be downloaded from <a href="http://ant.apache.org/">http://ant.apache.org</a></li>
	<li>The latest version of MPXJ from CVS. Details of the MPXJ CVS repository and how to use it can be found <a href="http://sourceforge.net/cvs/?group_id=70649" target="_blank">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
Here are the steps required to build MPXJ, they assume that both Java and Ant
are available on the path.
<ol>
	<li>Change directory to the ant subdirectory of the MPXJ folder.</li>
	<li>At your command prompt, execute the command "ant clean". This will
	remove any temporary files or previous output from the build process.</li>
	<li>At your command prompt, execute the command "ant archive". This will
	build the JAR file.</li>
	<li>That's it! The file mpxj.jar should now be sat in the root of your
	MPXJ folder.</li>	
</ol> 
</p>
</section>

<section name="Building the .NET DLLs">
<p>Building the .NET DLL version of MPXJ uses the same steps described for
building the Java JAR file, but with the additional prerequisite that IKVM 
is availabale on your system. The steps required are as follows.
<ol>
<li>Download IKVM from 
<a href="http://www.ikvm.net/" target="_blank">http://www.ikvm.net</a> and
unzip the files into a convenient directory.</li>
<li>Change directory to the ant subdirectory of the MPXJ folder.</li>
<li>Edit the build.xml file and ensure that the property named ikvm.dir is 
set to point to the location where you have unzipped IKVM.</li>
<li>Now you can follow the steps described above ro build the Java JAR file. 
The Ant script will recognise that IKVM is present and build the .NET DLL 
in the lib.net folder.</li>
</ol>
</p>
</section>

<section name="Building the Javadoc">
<p>The most recent Javadocs for MPXJ are always available at 
<a href="http://mpxj.sf.net/" target="_blank">http://mpxj.sf.net</a>, however
if you wish to build a local copy for yourself, follow the instructions above
to build the MPXJ JAR, then at the command prompt enter the command 
"ant document", which will then generate the Javadoc in the doc/api folder.</p>
</section>

<section name="Generating the JAXB code">
<p>The XML schema file from which the JAXB code has been generated is
supplied by Microsoft as part of the Microsoft Project SDK, which can be
downloaded from MSDN. 
Normally you will not need to regenerate this source, but if you are changing 
the JAXB implementation, or modifying the use of JAXB in some way, then you
may need to regenerate this code.</p>

<p>If you obtain a copy of the XML schema file from the SDK, you can rebuild 
the JAXB source using the xjc target found in the ant build.xml file. 
Note that the xjc target is platform specific, you will need to 
change the name of xjc tool to be xjc.bat, xjc.exe, or xjc.sh 
depending on your operating system. You will also need to set 
the properties indicated in build.xml to tell it where to 
find xjc and the xsd file.</p>
</section>

</body>
</document>




