<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>
   <properties>
      <title>MPXJ Changes</title> 
      <author email="jon.iles@tapsterrock.com">Jon Iles</author> 
   </properties> 

   <body> 

   <release version="0.0.26" date="CVS HEAD"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added a flag called "expanded" to the Task class to represent whether a task in an MPP9 file is shown as expanded or collapsed by MS Project.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug in the relation code in MpxjQuery (contributed by Shlomo Swidler).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Modified MPXDateFormat, MPXTimeFormat and MPXCurrencyFormat to derive them from DateFormat and NumberFormat.</action>
   </release>
      
   <release version="0.0.25" date="11/08/2005"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for reading all properties from an MPP9 file which define the visual appearance of the Gantt Chart view shown in Microsoft Project (development funding courtesy of Steelray).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Tidied up constructors. Added no-argument constructors to the MPPFile and MSPDIFile classes.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Fixed incorrect value in WorkGroup enumerated type.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Implemented the resource assignment work contour property (contributed by Wade Golden).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Implemented correct handling for MPX files using different character set encodings (suggested by Frank Illenberger).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed task duration calculation when importing an MPP file with a "non-standard" hours-per-day setting (contributed by Wade Golden).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to ensure that the MPX task fixed attribute, and the MPP/MSPDI task type attribute are correctly handled.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to implement the remaining project header attributes supported by the MSPDI file format.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to add support for reading the MPX 3.0 files generated by Primavera (courtesy of CapitalSoft).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed incorrect assumptions about conversion of durations to hours when writing MPX files (contributed by Frank Illenberger).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to calculate remaining work for resource assignments on import, to allow MSPDI export of this data to work correctly (contributed by Frank Illenberger).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Updated to add another condition to the test for deleted tasks in MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Updated to fix a problem with reading assignment data from MPP9 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Rationalised the location of the JUnit tests and the sample files.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a problem where the project start and end dates reported in the project header were incorrect.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed an array out of bounds exception when reading an MPP9 file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to allow MPXCalendarHours to accept an arbitrary number of time periods.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Introduced the Day class to replace the use of arbitrary integers to represent days of the week.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added the ability to query the task assignments for a resource using the Resource.getTaskAssignments() method.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a problem with number formats in MSPDI files.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated the MPP View class to extract the view type.</action>            
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to ensure that duration values read from an MSPDI file are converted into the appropriate duration units, rather than being left as hours as the durations are represented in the MSPDI file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented French MPX file format translation (contributed by Benoit Baranne).</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug reading assignment work contour attribute.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to make failure more graceful when a Microsoft Project 4.0 MPP file is encountered.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where deleted constraints in an MPP9 file were were not being ignored.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to make replace the int relation type in the Relation class with instances of the RelationType class.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to derive RelationList from AbstractList.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added sample code to MpxjQuery to illustrate retrieval of information from Relation instances.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated MpqjQuery to parse MSPDI files as well as MPP and MPX files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for early start, early finish, late start, late finish to MPP files.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated MPP9 file support to handle start as late as possible constraints. </action>            
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for sub project file information in MPP9 files.</action>      
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where occasionally a task in MPP9 files were not beng read.</action>            
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a NegativeArrayIndexException thrown when reading certain MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Reduced the memory used by MPXJ by anything up to 60%, particularly when reading large MPP files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug when reading MPX files where the field delimiter was not comma, and task relation lists contained more then one entry.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Updated to fix unreliable retrieval of project start and end dates from certain MPP files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed schedule from value in MSPDI files (contributed by Frank Illenberger).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug when reading durations in elapsed days from an MPP file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Tasks can now have arbitrary priority values. These values are mapped to/from the fixed MPP8/MPX priority values where necessary.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.24" date="10/01/2005"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug (again!) where deleted resource assignments in MPP9 files were still seen by MPXJ.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to use class instances instead of ints to represent some enumerated types.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to implement support for reading and writing all of the basic Resource attributes found in MSPDI files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to implement support for reading and writing all of the basic Task attributes found in MSPDI files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to implement support for reading and writing all of the basic Project Header attributes from MPP8 and MPP9 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Made MSPDI file parsing more robust to allow it by default to cope with non-schema-compliant XML in the same manner as MS Project. Implemented a new compatibility flag to allow this behaviour to be disabled in favour of strict parsing.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Merged DateTimeSettings, CurrencySettings, and DefaultSettings into the ProjectHeader class. This change makes the project header data easier to use as it is in a single place. It also makes the entities used to descibe a project consistent with the contents of the MPP and MSPDI file formats.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.23" date="17/11/2004"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where MPXJ was still using the default locale of the user's machine to create localised MPX files when a normal international MPX file was expected.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where the incorrect record delimiter was being used in by the MPX RelationList class.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where the method Task.getText21 was not retrieving the correct text value.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where the task unique ID values were being truncated unnecessarily.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where calendar exceptions were not testing the range of dates between the start and end date correctly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where the priority of a task was being escalated when converting between an MPP9 file and an MSPDI file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where a deadline was incorrectly being added to a task when importing data from an MPP9 file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where deleted resource assignments in MPP9 files were still seen by MPXJ.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where MPXFile attributes were not being correctly copied by the copy constructor.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a rounding error in MPXCalendar.getDaysInRange (contributed by Wade Golden)</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to make MPXJ more robust in the face of unexpected offsets in MPP8 file format.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated support for password protected files to allow write reserved files to be read.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to use the latest version of JAXB, as shipped in Sun's Java Web Services Developer Pack (JWSDP) version  1.4.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated the distribution to include the redistributable files from the JWSDP JAXB implementation. Users will no longer need to download JWSDP separately in order to make use of MPXJ's MSPDI functionality.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to prevent empty notes records being added to tasks and resources when reading an MSPDI file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to improve accuracy when converting an MPP file to an MSPDI file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for blank task rows in MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for blank resource rows in MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for Portuguese MPX files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support reading and writing extended attributes (apart from outline codes) for MSPDI files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for the Resource Type attribute.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.22" date="27/07/2004"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where task data was not being read correctly from very large MPP9 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where certain MPP8 files were not read correctly when no constraint data is present.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where certain MPP9 files were not read correctly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where MPP9 files containing invalid resource data were not read correctly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where MPXJ was using the default locale of the user's machine to create localised MPX files when a normal international MPX file was expected.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where MPXJ not correctly handling embedded line breaks when reading and writing MPX files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Removed arbitrary restrictions on the number of various entities, originally taken from the MPX spec.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated MPX documentation for Task.getFixed and Task.setFixed.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated MPP9 file code to improve handling invalid offset values.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to remove leading and trailing spaces from MPX task field names before processing.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to detect password protected files and raise a suitable exception.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented an enhancement to improve file loading speed by an order of magnitude for files with a large number of tasks or resources (based on a contribution by Brian Leach).</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented support for Maven.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Updated MpxCreate utility to allow it to create both MPX and MSPDI files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added new JUnit test for confidential customer data.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for the resource assignment remaining work attribute for MPP8, MPP9 and MSPDI files.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.21" date="06/05/2004"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where the task start date attribute was not always correct for MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing valid tasks to be incorrectly identified as being deleted in MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing en exception when reading certain MPP9 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to allow localised MPX files to be written and read.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented support for German MPX files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented generic mechanism for dealing with task field aliases.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented task field alias read/write for MSPDI files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented task field alias read for MPP9 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented resource field alias read/write for MSPDI files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented resource field alias read for MPP9 files.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.20" date="15/03/2004"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where alternative decimal delimiters and thousands separators were not being handled correctly when reading and writing MPX files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing a null pointer exception when writing an MSPDI file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug in MSPDI files where default values were being written incorrectly for some task attributes.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug with MSPDI file date handling in non GMT time zones.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug in processing calendar data where data block is not a multiple of 12 bytes</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug processing tables where column data is null</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed checkstyle code warnings.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed Eclipse code warnings.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to include version 2.5 of the POI library.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for task calendars.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.19" date="02/12/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug reading table data from certain MPP8 files</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated MSPDI support to use latest version of JAXB (from JWSDP-1.3)</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Reimplemented base and resource calendars as a single MPXCalendar class</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated support for base calendars and resource calendars for all file formats</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Improved MPXException to print details of any nested exception when a stack trace is printed.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="remove">Removed unnecessary use of ByteArray.java</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for the following task fields: ActualOvertimeCost, ActualOvertimeWork, FixedCostAccrual, Hyperlink, HyperlinkAddress, HyperlinkSubAddress, LevelAssignments, LevelingCanSplit, LevelingDelay, PreleveledStart, PreleveledFinish, RemainingOvertimeCost, RemainingOvertimeWork.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.18" date="13/11/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug with writing MS Project compatible MSPDI XML files in non-GMT timezones.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug with writing MSPDI XML files in non-GMT timezones.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing an exception when zero length calendar names were present</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing MPP8 flags to be read incorrectly. Note that flag 20 is still not read correctly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug with the "Microsoft Project Compatible Output" flag for MSPDI files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug reading task text 10.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added new MPXFile.setIgnoreTextModel() method to allow MPXJ to ignore faulty text version of task or resource model records in MPX files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Improved invalid MPX data error handling and reporting.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added BaseCalendar.getDate method to allow end dates to be calculated based on a start date and a duration of working time.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Made MPXDateFormat implement java.io.Serializable to allow MPXDate to serialize correctly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated the ant build file to allow MPXJ to be built without the components that depend on JAXB</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Rationalised setDefaultStartTime and setDefaultEndTime methods</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added MppXml utility</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for querying view information held in MPP files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for querying table information held in MPP files. (NB This allows the user to retrieve column information, including user defined column names)</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for outlinecode1-10 fields in MPP9 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for resource "available from" and "available to" fields.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Verified that MPXJ will read MPP files written by Microsoft Project 2003 (they are still MPP9 files).</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.17" date="05/08/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where a decimal point was being appended to the currency format even if no decimal digits were required.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug where special characters appearing in the currency symbol were not being quoted.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug that caused resource assignments to be incorrectly read from some MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added a new write method to MPXFile allowing the user control over the character encoding used when writing an MPX file.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.16" date="04/07/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed bug causing some extended boolean attributes to be read incorrectly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed bug causing MPP8 file task data to be read incorrectly under certain circumstances.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated calendar duration code to account for calendar exceptions.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.15" date="17/06/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing resource assignments to be duplicated in an MPX file created programatically.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing an incorrect duration value to be read from an MPP9 file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing invalid MPX files to be written in locales which don't use a period as the decimal separator.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug causing embedded quote and comma characters in task and resource notes to be handled incorrectly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added simple JUnit test to demonstrate iteration through relationships.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added an example of programatically creating a partially complete task to the MPXCreate.java example.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added default values to the MPX project header.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for reading the RemainingDuration field from an MPP9 file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated predecessor and successor method documentation.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated Task.get/set ResourceInitials and Task.get/set ResourceNames method documentation.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from resource assignment data in MPP files which were previously not imported: ActualCost, ActualWork, Cost, Finish, Start, Units, Work.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.14" date="28/05/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from resource data in an MPP9 file which were previously not imported: Flag1-Flag20.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added the method MPPFile.getFileType to allow the type of MPP file (MPP8: 98, MPP9: 2000,2002) to be determined.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated API to make classes final and constructors package access only where appropriate.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to use of 6 byte long int fields for cost and work values for MPP8.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed error in reading task fixed cost for MPP8.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from task data in an MPP8 file which were previously not imported: Contact, Cost1-Cost10, Date1-Date10, Duration1-Duration10, EffortDriven, Finish1-Finish10, Flag1-Flag20, HideBar, Milestone, Number1-Number20, Rollup, Start1-Start10, Text1-Text30, Type, WBS.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from resource data in an MPP8 file which were previously not imported: Code, Cost1-Cost10, Date1-Date10, Duration1-Duration10, EmailAddress, Finish1-Finish10, Number1-Number20, Start1-Start10, Text1-Text30</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for task and resource note fields in MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for the OvertimeCost task attribute for all file formats.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract calendar data from MPP8 files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated resource notes to fix end of line handling problem.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added functionality to read default settings and currency settings data from MPP files.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.13" date="22/05/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Implemented support for the Microsoft Project 98 file format.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed a bug that prevented task and resource note text from being read.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to remove a Java 1.4 dependency introduced in 0.0.12. Will now work with Java 1.3.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to correct handling of carriage returns embedded in note fields.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.12" date="08/05/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed incorrect handling of timezones and daylight saving time.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed incorrect task structure generated from outline levels.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the notes fields from tasks and resources read from an MPP file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added the option to remove or preserve the RTF formatting from the note fields from an MPP file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from task data in an MPP file which were previously not imported: Text11-Text30, Number6-Number20, Duration4-Duration10, Date1-Date10, Cost4-Cost10, Start6-Start10, Finish6-Finish10</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from resource data in an MPP file which were previously not imported: Text6-Text30, Start1-Start10, Finish1-Finish10, Number1-Number20, Duration1-Duration10, Date1-Date10, Cost1-Cost10</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.11" date="15/04/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed error in format string used in one of the example files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed error where double byte characters were being read incorrectly.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed error where deleted constraints were being resurrected when read from an MPP file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from task data in an MPP file which were previously not imported: Flag11-Flag20, Rollup, HideBar, EffortDriven.</action>
   </release>


   <release version="0.0.10" date="08/04/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Corrected Actual Start and Actual End fields from MPP file.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed bug where time values were being broken by daylight saving time in the user's default locale.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from task data in an MPP file which were previously not imported: Actual Work, Baseline Work, Cost Variance, Deadline, Remaining Work, Work.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="update">Updated to extract the following fields from resource data in an MPP file which were previously not imported: Actual Cost, Actual Overtime Cost, Actual Work, Baseline Work, Cost, Cost Variance, Max Units, Overtime Cost, Overtime Rate, Overtime Work, Peak, Regular work, Remaining Cost, Remaining Overtime Cost, Remaining Work, Standard Rate, Work, Work Variance</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.9" date=""> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed bug when handling certain types of modified MPP file where resources have been updated.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added sample MPP files for bugs to the JUnit tests.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for summary flag import from MPP files.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added automatic summary flag update when creating an MPX file programatically.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added new constructor to the MSPDIFile class to allow MSPDI files to be created from scratch.</action>
   </release>

   <release version="0.0.8" date="27/03/2003"> 
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added support for estimated durations.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="fix">Fixed bug in handling certain types of modified MPP file where tasks have been updated.</action>
      <action dev="joniles" type="add">Added the facility to auto generate outline numbers.</action>
   </release>

   </body>
</document>



