<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>


<document>
   <properties>
      <title>How To: Convert project data from one format to another</title> 
      <author email="jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">Jon Iles</author> 
   </properties> 

   <body> 

<section name="How To: Convert project data from one format to another">

<p>To convert project data between different formats you read the source 
data using an appropriate Reader class, the write the data using a Writer
class which matches the format you want to convert to.</p>

<p>MPXJ can do a lot of the work for you, as the example below illustrates.
This example works where you have source and target file formats which can be
easily recognised by the file extension (for example .mpp, .mpx, .xer, and so on)</p>

<source>
import net.sf.mpxj.ProjectFile;
import net.sf.mpxj.reader.ProjectReader;
import net.sf.mpxj.reader.ProjectReaderUtility;
import net.sf.mpxj.writer.ProjectWriter;
import net.sf.mpxj.writer.ProjectWriterUtility;

...

ProjectReader reader = ProjectReaderUtility.getProjectReader(inputFile);
ProjectFile projectFile = reader.read(inputFile);

ProjectWriter writer = ProjectWriterUtility.getProjectWriter(outputFile);
writer.write(projectFile, outputFile);
</source>

<p>If you already explicitly know the file types you are converting between,
you can use the specific Reader and Writer classes, as shown below.</p>


<source>
import net.sf.mpxj.ProjectFile;
import net.sf.mpxj.reader.ProjectReader;
import net.sf.mpxj.writer.ProjectWriter;
import net.sf.mpxj.mpp.MPPReader;
import net.sf.mpxj.mpx.MPXWriter;
...

ProjectReader reader = new MPPReader();
ProjectFile projectFile = reader.read(inputFile);

ProjectWriter writer = new MPXWriter();
writer.write(projectFile, outputFile);
</source>

<p>
The following conversions are possible using MPXJ:
<ul>
<li>Microsoft Project MPP to Microsoft Project MPX</li>
<li>Microsoft Project MPP to Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI)</li>
<li>Microsoft Project MPP to Gnome Planner</li>
<li>Microsoft Project MPX to Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI)</li>
<li>Microsoft Project MPX to Gnome Planner</li>
<li>Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI) to Microsoft Project MPX</li>
<li>Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI) to Gnome Planner</li>
<li>Microsoft Project MPD to Microsoft Project MPX</li>
<li>Microsoft Project MPD to Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI)</li>
<li>Microsoft Project MPD to Gnome Planner</li>
<li>Primavera PM XML to Microsoft Project MPX</li>
<li>Primavera PM XML to Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI)</li>
<li>Primavera PM XML to Gnome Planner</li>
<li>Primavera XER to Microsoft Project MPX</li>
<li>Primavera XER to Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI)</li>
<li>Primavera XER to Gnome Planner</li>
<li>Gnome Planner to Microsoft Project MPX</li>
<li>Gnome Planner to Microsoft Project XML (MSPDI)</li>
</ul>
</p>
</section>

</body>
</document>




