<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>


<document>
   <properties>
      <title>Microsoft Project Exchange</title> 
      <author email="jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">Jon Iles</author> 
   </properties> 

   <body> 

<section name="Introduction">

<p>Welcome to MPXJ! This library provides a set of facilities to
allow project information to be manipulated in Java and .Net. MPXJ supports
seven data formats, Microsoft Project Exchange (MPX), Microsoft
Project (MPP,MPT), Microsoft Project Data Interchange (MSPDI XML), Microsoft 
Project Database (MPD), Planner (XML), and Primavera (XER and database).</p>

<p>The library is currently based around a set of structures
modelled on the data described by the MPP file format. All
manipulation of project data takes place using these data
structures, which can be read from or written to the various
supported file formats. The notes in the following paragraphs explain the
facilities MPXJ offers for each file format.</p>

<ul>
<li><b>MPX:</b> The MPX file format can be read by all versions of Microsoft
Project, and written by all versions up to Microsoft Project 98.
MPXJ allows MPX files to be created, read and written. See
<a href="http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=KB;EN-US;Q270139" target="_blank">
http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=KB;EN-US;Q270139</a> 
for a definition of the file format.</li>

<li><b>MPP:</b> The MPP file format is Microsoft's proprietary way of storing
project data. MPXJ supports read only access to MPP files produced
by Microsoft Project 98, Microsoft Project 2000, Microsoft 
Project 2002, Microsoft Project 2003, Microsoft Project 2007, and Microsoft Project 2010.
MPP template files, with the suffix MPT are also supported.</li>

<li><b>MSPDI:</b> The MSPDI file format is Microsoft's XML file format for
storing project data. Microsoft Project 2002, Microsoft Project
2003 and Microsoft Project 2007 can read and write MSPDI files. 
MPXJ allows MSPDI files to be created, read, and written. Documentation for the 
Project 2003 MSPDI file format can be 
<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=FE118952-3547-420A-A412-00A2662442D9" target="_blank">
downloaded from the MSDN web site</a> as part of the Office 2003 
XML Reference Schemas package. Documentation for the Project 2007 MSPDI
file format can be 
<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=2672f6f9-7028-4b30-99a2-18cb1eed1abe" target="_blank">
downloaded from the MSDN web site</a> as part of the 
Microsoft Project 2007 SDK.
Documentation for the Project 2010 MSPDI file format can be 
<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=46007f25-b44e-4aa6-80ff-9c0e75835ad9" target="_blank">downloaded from the MSDN web site</a>
as part of the Microsoft Project 2010 SDK. 
</li>

<li><b>MPD:</b> The MPD file format is an Access database file format used to
store one or more projects. The database schema used in these databases is 
also close to that used by Microsoft Project Server. MPXJ can read projects
stored in an MPD file using a JDBC connection. It is possible that MPXJ could 
also read the same data from a Microsoft Project Server database using the
same approach - but I haven't tried this!</li>

<li><b>PLANNER:</b> Planner is an Open Source project management too which uses
an XML file format to store project data. MPXJ read and write the Planner
file format.</li>

<li><b>PRIMAVERA:</b> Primavera is a high end project planning tool favoured
by users with complex planning requirements. It can export project data in the 
form of an XER file which MPXJ can read. It is also possible for MPXJ to connect
directly to the Primavera database via JDBC to read project data.</li>
</ul>
</section>

<section name="Java, .Net, PHP...">
<p>MPXJ is written and maintained in Java, however this is no barrier to
using its functionality in .Net or PHP applications.</p>

<p>Thanks to the facilities 
provided by IKVM, the MPXJ distribution also contains a native .Net DLL version
of MPXJ and its library dependencies. This allows MPXJ to be used 
from any .Net programming language (for example, C#, Visual Basic 
and so on), without having to be aware that the original code was written 
in Java. As part of the MPXJ release process the Java and .Net libraries
are both exercised using the same set of regression tests to ensure that their
behaviour is identical. Both the Java and .Net versions of the library
are used in production commercial applications - so you can confident
that the code will work for you!</p>

<p>One option for working with the functionality offered by MPXJ in your
PHP application is to use a library like 
<a href="http://php-java-bridge.sourceforge.net " target="_blank">PHP/Java Bridge</a>.
PHP/Java Bridge can be used to expose the complete MPXJ API in PHP: you don't
have to work in Java, C# or VB in order to work with Microsoft Project files.</p>
</section>

<section name="Getting started with MPXJ in Java">

<p>The latest release of MPXJ can be downloaded from the project's
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=70649">SourceForge download page</a>.
The core MPXJ functionality is contained in the mpxj.jar file, which you
will find in the root folder of the MPXJ distribution.
The library is simple to use, and to illustrate this, a
small number of sample files have been included in the utility
source package of the distribution.</p>

<p>The MPP functionality depends on the 
<a href="http://poi.apache.org/" target="_blank">POI</a> library.
In order to use the MPP functionality in MPXJ, the
POI JAR file must be present on your classpath. A copy of this
library can be found in the lib directory of the MPXJ distribution.</p>
</section>

<section name="Getting started with MPXJ and .Net">

<p>The latest release of MPXJ can be downloaded from the project's
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=70649">SourceForge download page</a>.
The core MPXJ functionality is contained in the mpxj.dll file, which you
will find in the lib.net folder of the MPXJ distribution. To use the library
you will also need to ensure that the IKVM runtime DLLs are in visible to .Net.
These are also provided in the lib.net folder of the MPXJ distribution.</p>

<p>The library is simple to use, and to illustrate this, a
small number of sample files have been included in the utility
source package of the distribution.</p>

<p>The MPP functionality depends on the 
<a href="http://poi.apache.org/" target="_blank">POI</a> library.
In order to use the MPP functionality in MPXJ, the
POI DLL file must be visible to .Net. A copy of this
library can be found in the lib.net folder of the MPXJ distribution.</p>
</section>


<section name="Keep in touch">

<p>We're keen to hear from you about how you are using MPXJ,
please 
<a href="mailto:jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">drop me a note</a>. 
If you use MPXJ as a part of an application that you redistribute,
commercially or otherwise, drop us a line and we'll include
a link to your website on the MPXJ page</p>
</section>


<section name="You can help us">
<p>Please let us know what features you'd like to see added
to MPXJ. In addition, the MPP functionality is not
complete as we have had to reverse engineer the data from
the MPP file format, so we need to know if you have MPP
files that can't be read, or don't contain the data you
expect. The more of this feedback you can give us, the
better we can make MPXJ!</p>
<p>We also very much welcome contributions of code to MPXJ. 
Please note however that by contributing code to MPXJ, you
are assigning copyright for that code to Packwood Software.
It is important for us to ensure that their is a single
copyright owner for MPXJ to ensure that we can enforce the
terms of MPXJ's license agreement where they are violated.</p>
</section>

<section name="We can help you">
<p>Are you developing a commercial product that uses MPXJ?
Do you want to integrate MPXJ into your application? Is
MPXJ missing a feature critical to your business? If the
answer to any of these questions is yes, we can help you!
We offer commercial development services and consultancy
for users of MPXJ at competitive rates. Please  
<a href="mailto:jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">get in
touch by mailing me</a>
to see how we can work together.</p>
</section>

<section name="Licensing">
<p>MPXJ is distributed under the terms of the 
<a href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/licenses.html#LGPL" target="_blank">GNU LGPL</a>,
a copy of which can be found in the legal directory of the
distribution. Please read this license carefully! It will cost you nothing
to use MPXJ - but you must comply with the terms of the license. 
We have, and will continue to pursue any violations of the MPXJ LGPL 
that we are made aware of.</p>

<p>The functionality to read MPP files depends on the
use of the POI library. The license for this library can
be found in the legal directory of the distribution.</p>

<p>The functionality used to create .NET DLLs and the supporting libraries
it requires depend on IKVM and GNU Classpath. The licenses for these libraries
and utilities can be found in the legal directory of the distribution.</p>

<p>A copy of the JUnit library is provided for your
convenience to allow you to run the regression tests
provided with MPXJ. The license for JUnit can be found in
the legal directory of the distribution.</p>
</section>

<section name="Acknowledgements"> 
<p>This product includes software developed by the Apache Software Foundation (<a href="http://www.apache.org/" target="_blank">http://www.apache.org</a>)</p> 
<p>This product includes software developed by IKVM.NET (<a href="http://www.ikvm.net/" target="_blank">http://www.ikvm.net</a>)</p>
<p>This product includes software developed by the GNU Classpath Project (<a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/classpath/" target="_blank">http://www.gnu.org/software/classpath</a>)</p>
<p>This product includes software developed by the JUnit Project (<a href="http://www.junit.org/" target="_blank">http://www.junit.org</a>)</p> 
</section>

   </body> 
</document>

