<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>


<document>
   <properties>
      <title>Microsoft Project Exchange in Java</title> 
      <author email="jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">Jon Iles</author> 
   </properties> 

   <body> 

<section name="Introduction">

<p>Welcome to MPXJ! This library provides a set of facilities to
allow project information to be manipulated in Java. MPXJ supports
three file formats, Microsoft Project Exchange (MPX), Microsoft
Project (MPP,MPT), and Microsoft Project Data Interchange (MSPDI).</p>

<p>The library is currently based around a set of data structures
modelled on the data described by the MPX file format. All
manipulation of project data takes place using these data
structures, which can be read from or written to the various
supported file formats. The following notes explain what
facilities MPXJ offers for each file format.</p>

<p>MPX: The MPX file format can be read by all versions of Microsoft
Project, and written by all versions up to Microsoft Project 98.
MPXJ allows MPX files to be created, read and written. See
<a href="http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=KB;EN-US;Q270139" target="_blank">
http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=KB;EN-US;Q270139</a> 
for a definition of the file format.</p>

<p>MPP: The MPP file format is Microsoft's proprietary way of storing
project data. MPXJ supports read only access to MPP files produced
by Microsoft Project 98, Microsoft Project 2000, Microsoft 
Project 2002, and Microsoft Project 2003. MPP template files, with
the suffix MPT are also supported.</p>

<p>MSPDI: The MSPDI file format is Microsoft's XML file format for
storing project data. Microsoft Project 2002 and Microsoft Project
2003 can read and write MSPDI files. MPXJ allows MSPDI files to be 
created, read, and written. Documentation on the MSPDI file format
can be 
<a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/office/understanding/project/tools/default.aspx" target="_blank">
downloaded from the MSDN web site</a> as part of the Office 2003 
XML Reference Schemas package.</p>
</section>


<section name="Getting started">

<p>The latest release of MPXJ can be downloaded by following
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=70649">this link</a>.
The library is fairly simple to use, and to illustrate this, a
small number of sample files have been included in the utility
source package of the distribution.</p>

<p>The MPP functionality depends on the <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/poi/" target="_blank">POI</a> library produced by the
<a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/" target="_blank">Apache Jakarta</a> project. In order to use the MPP functionality the
POI JAR file must be present on your classpath. A copy of this
library can be found in the lib directory of the distribution.</p>

<p>The MSPDI functionality depends on the Sun JAXB implementation
as distributed in the Java Web Services Developer Pack version 1.4. 
In order to use the MSPDI functionality the
JAXB JAR files must be present on your classpath.
Copies of the relevant libraries can be found in the lib directory of the distribution.
The original distribution from which these redistributable files have been taken
can be found at:
<a href="http://java.sun.com/webservices/downloads/webservicespack.html" target="_blank">
http://java.sun.com/webservices/downloads/webservicespack.html</a></p>
</section>


<section name="JUnit">

<p>Should you wish to run the <a href="http://junit.sourceforge.net/" target="_blank">JUnit</a> tests provided with MPXJ, you
need to be aware that the JUnit classloader doesn't get on well
with JAXB, so it is recommended that you execute the JUnit test
runner with the -noloading command line option, or otherwise
disable class reloading.</p>
</section>


<section name="Build">

<p>If you want to build MPXJ yourself using the supplied source and
ant build.xml file, there are a few points to note:</p>

<p>The XML schema file from which the JAXB code has been generated is
supplied by Microsoft as part of the Microsoft Project 2002 and
Microsoft Project 2003 distributions. The file name is mspdi.xsd. 
This file is not distributed as part of MPXJ, but it can be
found on the Microsoft Project 2002 and 2003 CDs, and can also be 
<a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/office/understanding/project/tools/default.aspx" target="_blank">
downloaded from the MSDN web site</a> (look for the link to the 
Office 2003 Reference Schemas).</p>

<p>If you are able to obtain a copy of this file, you can rebuild 
the JAXB source using the xjc target found in the ant build.xml file. 
Note that the xjc target is platform specific, you will need to 
change the reference to the xjc tool to be xjc.bat or xjc.sh 
depending on your operating system. You will also need to set 
the properties indicated in build.xml to tell it where to 
find xjc and the xsd file.</p>
</section>

<section name="Keep in touch">

<p>We're keen to hear from you about how you are using MPXJ,
please 
<a href="mailto:jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">drop me a note</a>. 
If you use MPXJ as a part of an application that you redistribute,
commercially or otherwise, drop us a line and we'll include
a link to your website on the MPXJ page</p>
</section>


<section name="You can help">
<p>Please let us know what features you'd like to see added
to MPXJ. In addition, the MPP functionality is not
complete as we have had to reverse engineer the data from
the MPP file format, so we need to know if you have MPP
files that can't be read, or don't contain the data you
expect. The more of this feedback you can give us, the
better we can make MPXJ!</p>
</section>

<section name="We can help">
<p>Are you developing a commercial product that uses MPXJ?
Do you want to integrate MPXJ into your application? Is
MPXJ missing a feature critical to your business? If the
answer to any of these questions is yes, we can help you!
We offer commercial development services and consultancy
for users of MPXJ at competitive rates. Please  
<a href="mailto:jon.iles@bcs.org.uk">get in
touch by mailing me</a>
to see how we can work together.</p>
</section>

<section name="Licensing">
<p>MPXJ is distributed under the terms of the 
<a href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/licenses.html#LGPL" target="_blank">GNU LGPL</a>,
a copy of which can be found in the legal directory of the
distribution.</p>

<p>As mentioned above, the MPP functionality depends on the
use of the POI library. The license for this library can
be found in the legal directory of the distribution. To
comply with the Apache license, we must state that "this
product includes software developed by the Apache
Software Foundation (<a href="http://www.apache.org/" target="_blank">http://www.apache.org/</a>)."</p>

<p>A copy of the JUnit library is provided for you
convenience to allow you to run the regression tests
provided with MPXJ. The license for JUnit can be found in
the legal directory of the distribution.</p>
</section>

   </body> 
</document>

